<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <origin/>
                <pubdate>20240729</pubdate>
                <pubtime>142105</pubtime>
                <title>School District</title>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>School Districts from the Michigan Geographic Framework (MGF) base map. These are Local Education Agency (LEA) school districts as defined under MCL 380.6 and as organized under MCL 380.11a (general powers school district) or under part 6 (district of the first class) of the Revised School Code.</abstract>
            <purpose>MGF is the master repository for common shared GIS data. It provides statewide digital base mapping for all levels of government, academia, and both private and public sectors.</purpose>
        </descript>
        <status>
            <update>As needed</update>
        </status>
        <spdom>
            <bounding>
                <westbc>-92.208252</westbc>
                <eastbc>-81.968994</eastbc>
                <northbc>48.465637</northbc>
                <southbc>41.286062</southbc>
            </bounding>
        </spdom>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>None</themekt>
                <themekey>School Districts</themekey>
                <themekey>MGF</themekey>
                <themekey>Michigan</themekey>
            </theme>
            <theme>
                <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
                <themekey>planningCadastre</themekey>
            </theme>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>None</accconst>
        <useconst>This dataset is a public record and, as more fully described below, there are no restrictions on the use, reproduction, or distribution of this dataset. Notwithstanding the foregoing, the public release of this dataset should not be construed, expressed or implied, as to whether any use constitutes a legally permissible purpose. It is the sole responsibility of the user to determine if the data is usable for their purposes. This dataset is provided “AS IS” and on an “AS AVAILABLE” basis. The State of Michigan (“State”) makes no warranties, express or implied, regarding the accuracy, adequacy, reliability, timeliness, or completeness of this dataset. The State also does not make any warranties, express or implied, for the continued quality, accuracy, or currency of this dataset after it has been downloaded, nor the quality or accuracy of any analyses or re-uses of this dataset. THE STATE DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES WITH REGARD TO THIS DATASET AND ANY INFORMATION PROVIDED TO YOU, INCLUDING THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, AND NONINFRINGEMENT OF PROPRIETARY RIGHTS. THE STATE WILL NOT BE LIABLE, REGARDLESS OF THE FORM OF ACTION, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, TORT, NEGLIGENCE, STRICT LIABILITY OR BY STATUTE OR OTHERWISE, FOR ANY CLAIM FOR CONSEQUENTIAL, INCIDENTAL, INDIRECT, OR SPECIAL DAMAGES, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION LOST PROFITS AND LOST BUSINESS OPPORTUNITIES, RELATED TO THE ACCESS OR USE OF THIS DATASET. IN NO EVENT WILL THE STATE BE LIABLE FOR ANY AMOUNTS THAT MAY RESULT FROM THE ACCESS OR USE OF THIS DATASET, REGARDLESS OF THE FORM OF ACTION, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, TORT, NEGLIGENCE, STRICT LIABILITY, OR BY STATUTE OR OTHERWISE. You forever release the State, its departments, subdivisions, officers, and employees from all claims, rights, actions, demands, damages, liabilities, expenses and fees, which arise out of or relate to your access or use of this dataset. You must defend, indemnify and hold the State, its departments, subdivisions, officers, and employees harmless, without limitation, from and against all actions, claims, losses, liabilities, damages, costs, attorney fees, and expenses (including those required to establish the right to indemnification) arising out of or relating to your access or use of this dataset. The State reserves the right to modify or remove this dataset for any reason, without notice, at any time. Nothing in these terms constitutes or is intended to be a limitation upon, or waiver of, any privileges and immunities that apply to the State. These terms are governed by and interpreted under the laws of the State of Michigan without regard to conflict of laws provisions. These terms do not apply to other materials or content, including maps or logos, that may be located on the site or portal containing this dataset and that may be protected by intellectual property rights such copyright, trademark, or patent. Nothing in these terms should be construed, expressed or implied, as impacting any existing rights or licenses in such materials or content, if any.</useconst>
        <datacred>Center for Shared Solutions, Department of Technology, Management, and Budget, State of Michigan</datacred>
    </idinfo>
    <eainfo>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp>
                <enttypl>School Districts</enttypl>
                <enttypd>School districts layer from the Michigan Geographic Framework (MGF) base map</enttypd>
            </enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>FIPS Code</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Federal number identifying a school district (FIPS = Federal Information Processing Standards). Value assigned by the federal government to represent a school district. The FIPS numbering system differs from the State of Michigan numbering system. This school district layer is being distributed statewide. If a school district is split by a county boundary the polygon will not be split. The entire school district will be represented by a single polygon</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Department of Technology, Management, and Budget (DTMB) Center for Shared Solutions (CSS)</attrdefs>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Name</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Long school district name. The school district name is provided in title case style. For example, Eaton Rapids Schools will be provided as Eaton Rapids Public Schools</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Department of Technology, Management, and Budget (DTMB) Center for Shared Solutions (CSS)</attrdefs>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>DCode</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Michigan Department of Education code. Value assigned by the Michigan Department of Education to represent a school district</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Department of Technology, Management, and Budget (DTMB) Center for Shared Solutions (CSS)</attrdefs>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Map Layout</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Optimal map layout orientation to use when mapping polygon (landscape or portrait)</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Department of Technology, Management, and Budget (DTMB) Center for Shared Solutions (CSS)</attrdefs>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>FIPSNum</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Federal Number Identifying a School District. FIPSCODE as a numeric value</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Department of Technology, Management, and Budget (DTMB) Center for Shared Solutions (CSS)</attrdefs>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Label</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Short school district name. The school district name is provided as a short common name in title case. For example, Eaton Rapids Schools will be provided as Eaton Rapids</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Department of Technology, Management, and Budget (DTMB) Center for Shared Solutions (CSS)</attrdefs>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Type</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Type of polygon feature. The type will be School for the school district layer</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Department of Technology, Management, and Budget (DTMB) Center for Shared Solutions (CSS)</attrdefs>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>ISD</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Intermediate School District code. Value assigned by the Michigan Department of Education to represent an intermediate school district</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Department of Technology, Management, and Budget (DTMB) Center for Shared Solutions (CSS)</attrdefs>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>MGFVersion</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Michigan Geographic Framework version</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Department of Technology, Management, and Budget (DTMB) Center for Shared Solutions (CSS)</attrdefs>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Peninsula</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Which peninsula the data is displayed on (upper or lower)</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Department of Technology, Management, and Budget (DTMB) Center for Shared Solutions (CSS)</attrdefs>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape_Area</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>GIS calculated area of the polygon in meters</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Department of Technology, Management, and Budget (DTMB) Center for Shared Solutions (CSS)</attrdefs>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>GIS calculated length of the polygon perimeter in meters</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Department of Technology, Management, and Budget (DTMB) Center for Shared Solutions (CSS)</attrdefs>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
    </eainfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>Michigan Department of Technology, Management, and Budget - Center for Shared Solutions</cntorg>
                    <cntper>Tim Lauxmann</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>physical</addrtype>
                    <city>Lansing</city>
                    <state>MI</state>
                    <postal>48933</postal>
                    <country>US</country>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>517-898-5663</cntvoice>
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
